<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cameron&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cameron&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 21:01:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust &amp; More</title>
      <link>/2018/06/03/rust--more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 21:01:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/03/rust--more/</guid>
      <description>For the past two or so weeks I’ve been spending a lot of time writing Rust. Rust is a really spectacularly designed language with perhaps the greatest package manager⊕It’s called Cargo. I have ever experienced.
Rust is fascinating to me because it’s one of my first true compiled languages. In contrast to the other languages I’m somewhat good at:
 R (mostly interpereted) Python (interpereted) C# (JIT compiled) Julia (JIT compiled)  I am only passingly familiar with C and have mostly repressed C++, so Rust was both new and refreshing to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down With Business</title>
      <link>/2018/05/22/down-with-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 05:39:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/22/down-with-business/</guid>
      <description>From Martin Parker at the Guardian:
 We can see how this works if we look a bit more closely at the business-school curriculum and how it is taught. Take finance, for instance. This is a field concerned with understanding how people with money invest it. It assumes that there are people with money or capital that can be used as security for money, and hence it also assumes substantial inequalities of income and wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates</title>
      <link>/2018/05/12/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 15:08:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/12/updates/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to get better about writing more things. To that end, I figured I should post some general updates on the things I’ve done lately.
New York My brother and I just got back from a week-long trip to upstate New York to see our grandmother. She’s a cool lady, and we figured since we’re both sort of adults with jobs we should drop in. I raced BMX a little bit, wiped out a bit, and generally had a good time with cool folks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>/2018/04/19/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/19/phd/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to be a PhD student at the University of Oregon! I am looking forward to working with some spectacularly bright people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Papers</title>
      <link>/2018/04/05/scientific-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/05/scientific-papers/</guid>
      <description>An excellent article from the Atlantic explores the way that computational essays haven&amp;rsquo;t seemed to penetrate academia. There&amp;rsquo;s some information about the contest between open source and for-profit tools, like this:
 But it’s hard to sell the scientific community on a piece of commercial software. Even though Wolfram Research has given away a free Mathematica notebook viewer for years, and even though most major universities already have a site license that lets their students and faculty use Mathematica freely, it might be too much to ask publishers to abandon PDFs, an open format, for a proprietary product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Cards</title>
      <link>/2018/02/27/business-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/27/business-cards/</guid>
      <description>A couple months ago while I was bumming around London trying to get people to give me work, I made some (I think) really cool business card designs. I made a couple of different card designs that shared the same front and had varying backs. I have gotten some pretty good feedback whenever I’ve given these out.
All the designs are made by me in Adobe Illustrator. You can get similar cards made at moo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tufte Stufte</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/tufte-stufte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/tufte-stufte/</guid>
      <description>This is not a margin note.⊕This is a margin note. As you can see, it is to the right of the left, and it indeed appears to be smaller. Were it a margin note as one might presuppose, it would be to the right of the left and perhaps a bit smaller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Debt</title>
      <link>/2017/09/12/corporate-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/12/corporate-debt/</guid>
      <description>This strikes me as a strange use of corporate cash.
 Thirty US companies together have more than $800bn of fixed-income investments, according to a Financial Times analysis of their most recent filings with the US Securities and Exchange Commission.
 That’s a lot of money. You might be wondering who those thirty companies are, and it’s probably who you’d expect – tech companies with far too much cash sitting around collecting dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Dream</title>
      <link>/2017/09/03/the-american-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/03/the-american-dream/</guid>
      <description>Edmund Phelps writing at Project Syndicate:
 What made the American Dream distinctive was neither the hope of winning the lottery nor of being buoyed by national market forces or public policy. It was the hope of achieving things, with all that that entails: drawing on one’s personal knowledge, trusting one’s intuition, venturing into the unknown. It reflected the deep need of these Americans to have the experience of succeeding at something: a craftsman’s gratification at seeing his mastery result in better work, or a merchant’s satisfaction at seeing “his ship come in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flash Crash</title>
      <link>/2017/08/26/the-flash-crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/26/the-flash-crash/</guid>
      <description>A paper came out in the April 2017 edition of the Journal of Finance that I found to be absolutely fascinating. Normally I’d just put a link up on Twitter and move on, but leaving Facebook and Twitter have limited my ability to scream about cool papers. I thought I’d do a brief post about the paper and talk about why it’s interesting to me.
The abstract:
 We study intraday market intermediation in an electronic market before and during a period of large and temporary selling pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Pronunciation</title>
      <link>/2017/08/16/english-pronunciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/16/english-pronunciation/</guid>
      <description>My last name tends to throw a lot of people off, because it has far too many f&amp;rsquo;s and not enough real letters. While doing a bit of research on how to tell people how to best pronounce my name (it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;fye-fur&amp;rdquo;, not &amp;ldquo;fiffer&amp;rdquo;), I found a neat little poem designed to showcase some of the strange ways English pronounces words. I sent it out to a couple of my friends from Norway and Greece and they politely declined to try a live reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Numbers</title>
      <link>/2017/08/15/perfect-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/15/perfect-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I just started reading a book called How to Prove It: A Structured Approach, a book all about writing and understanding proofs. My unconventional background in mathematics means that I have a fair bit of terror when it comes to proofs; they have often come up on more quantitative finance courses in a tangential manner, as the proofs are often unnessecary. The fact remains that I am terrified by them, and wanted to get over my fear of proofs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Paper on Cointegration in Crude Oil</title>
      <link>/2017/08/06/a-brief-paper-on-cointegration-in-crude-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/06/a-brief-paper-on-cointegration-in-crude-oil/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished putting the final touches on my final paper for my master&amp;rsquo;s degree, and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write up a bit about the process. You can get the fancy LaTeX version here.
My final summer course for the master&amp;rsquo;s program was all about Energy Finance, taught by an econometrician1. Commensurate with the professor&amp;rsquo;s experience, the final paper was along the same lines. We were allowed to choose between three different project options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia</title>
      <link>/2017/07/05/julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/05/julia/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m wrapping up my master&amp;rsquo;s degree, I have somehow managed to find a large amount of time to pursue personal interests. One of those interests is Julia, a technical computing language with C-comparable speed. I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure where I stumbled on it, but it stuck with me. Of course, the best way to learn something is to do something cool with it, and FiveThiryEight&amp;rsquo;s Riddler often tends to supply great cannon fodder for programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle Titanic</title>
      <link>/2017/05/23/kaggle-titanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/23/kaggle-titanic/</guid>
      <description>I thought I’d start getting into Kaggle to work on some non-finance data to get a feel for the messiness of real-world information. Kaggle’s introductory competition is about predicting which passengers on the Titanic are going to survive using a handful of features, so let’s launch into mucking about. This post follows a “lab book” style and is quite scattered, as I develop ideas about what to do.
# Libraries library(tidyverse) ## Warning: package &amp;#39;purrr&amp;#39; was built under R version 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of DIY Quants</title>
      <link>/2017/05/16/the-rise-of-diy-quants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/16/the-rise-of-diy-quants/</guid>
      <description>This post first appeared in the May 2017 edition of the Reading University Investment Society newspaper - you can find a copy of the whole paper here.
Modern finance is a constantly evolving field. In the 1970s after Black-Scholes published their seminal paper, derivatives in their current form (for primitive derivatives are found as far back as in ancient Sumerian culture) became common and ubiquitous. Approximately ten years later, we saw the rise of the first quantitative powerhouse Renaissance Technologies, a firm that to this day makes absurd profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages</title>
      <link>/2017/05/13/github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/13/github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved my site away from zeit, and migrated it to GitHub Pages. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to maintain the site with git than with zeit&amp;rsquo;s now feature, which is a little too high-powered for my tases.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also changed the theme to a modified version of paperback. The colors were originally all sepia tone, and I liked the current color scheme and typography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Risk &amp; Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/2017/05/01/credit-risk--logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/01/credit-risk--logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>I thought I’d do a little bit of analysis to showcase some credit risk analysis, using logistic regression. I’ve pulled this sample loan data from a DataCamp course on credit risk. It’s a cool class, you should check it out if you have time. In a later post, I will try this same analysis with a neural network to see if it has better predictive capabilities.
Here’s a look at the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I made a newspaper</title>
      <link>/2017/05/01/i-made-a-newspaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/01/i-made-a-newspaper/</guid>
      <description>A couple of my friends here at the University of Reading came up with an excellent idea to start a financial newspaper. The concept was that the society1 would collect articles on investing and other things finance and publish them in a monthly paper. Being one of the few native English speakers with an interest in editing and journalism, I was selected to run the paper as Chief Editor.
I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of the results, you can find the finished version of the April edition here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished building this site with Hugo and blogdown, an excellent R package built up by the folks at RStudio. The first iteration of this site is being hosted by zeit, a super interesting cloud company. Deployment takes about a minute, unlike the absolute nightmare that is Google Cloud. They take Dockerfiles as well, something that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any experience with until lately.
As this is the first blog post here, I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d lay out a bit of why I built this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federal Funds Hike</title>
      <link>/2017/04/16/federal-funds-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/16/federal-funds-hike/</guid>
      <description>This article first appeared in the Reading University Investment Society&amp;rsquo;s April edition on April 16th, 2017.
Last month, the Federal Reserve raised the short-term interest rate target range by 0.25%, to a range of 0.75% to 1%. This is in line with the central bank’s “slow and steady” approach to rate increases after a decade of historically low interest rates, and is the third such rate increase since June of 2006.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEX&#39;s Crumbling Quote</title>
      <link>/2017/04/16/iexs-crumbling-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/16/iexs-crumbling-quote/</guid>
      <description>This article first appeared in the Reading University Investment Society&amp;rsquo;s April edition on April 16th, 2017.
The Investor’s Exchange, also referred to as IEX, came to prominence in 2014 after Michael Lewis’ book Flash Boys was released. IEX was designed as an exchange to protect lumbering buy side firms from high-frequency traders and other nimble market actors.
Their first innovation was to treat what is referred to as stale quote arbitrage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>