<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Cameron Pfiffer</title>
    <link>/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Cameron Pfiffer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Cameron Pfiffer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia</title>
      <link>/post/2017-07-05-julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-07-05-julia/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m wrapping up my master&amp;rsquo;s degree, I have somehow managed to find a large amount of time to pursue personal interests. One of those interests is Julia, a technical computing language with C-comparable speed. I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure where I stumbled on it, but it stuck with me. Of course, the best way to learn something is to do something cool with it, and FiveThiryEight&amp;rsquo;s Riddler often tends to supply great cannon fodder for programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages</title>
      <link>/post/2017-05-13-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-05-13-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved my site away from zeit, and migrated it to GitHub Pages. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to maintain the site with git than with zeit&amp;rsquo;s now feature, which is a little too high-powered for my tases.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also changed the theme to a modified version of paperback. The colors were originally all sepia tone, and I liked the current color scheme and typography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/2017-04-30-hugo-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-04-30-hugo-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished building this site with Hugo and blogdown, an excellent R package built up by the folks at RStudio. The first iteration of this site is being hosted by zeit, a super interesting cloud company. Deployment takes about a minute, unlike the absolute nightmare that is Google Cloud. They take Dockerfiles as well, something that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any experience with until lately.
As this is the first blog post here, I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d lay out a bit of why I built this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m looking for work! If you need a financial analyst, data scientist, or just a quick learner, you can contact me at cpfiffer@gmail.com.
I&amp;rsquo;m a graduate student in finance. I also play with code, and occasionally piano. This is a little website I built, partly as a portfolio of some of the stuff I can do, but also because it&amp;rsquo;s fun.
I have a master&amp;rsquo;s in finance from the ICMA Centre at the Henley Business School (which itself is part of the University of Reading1) Nominally, my degree is in corporate finance, though I&amp;rsquo;ve studied most business disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>