<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journalism on Cameron&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/journalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journalism on Cameron&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/journalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I made a newspaper</title>
      <link>/2017/05/01/i-made-a-newspaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/01/i-made-a-newspaper/</guid>
      <description>A couple of my friends here at the University of Reading came up with an excellent idea to start a financial newspaper. The concept was that the society1 would collect articles on investing and other things finance and publish them in a monthly paper. Being one of the few native English speakers with an interest in editing and journalism, I was selected to run the paper as Chief Editor.
I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of the results, you can find the finished version of the April edition here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEX&#39;s Crumbling Quote</title>
      <link>/2017/04/16/iexs-crumbling-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/16/iexs-crumbling-quote/</guid>
      <description>This article first appeared in the Reading University Investment Society&amp;rsquo;s April edition on April 16th, 2017.
The Investor’s Exchange, also referred to as IEX, came to prominence in 2014 after Michael Lewis’ book Flash Boys was released. IEX was designed as an exchange to protect lumbering buy side firms from high-frequency traders and other nimble market actors.
Their first innovation was to treat what is referred to as stale quote arbitrage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>